A.E. (Gene) Magee Photographs and Papers 1902-1996 (bulk 1930-1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Arizona, circa 1930-1984; Series 2
  - Miscellaneous, undated; Subseries 2
    This series is described at folder level and arranged alphabetically and contains mostly black and white and some color negatives and prints and color slides from unidentified locations or national and state parks.
    - Arizona National and State Parks: Chiricahua Mountains, Grand Canyon, Montezuma's Castle, Painted Desert, Petrified Forest, Sunset Crater, Walnut Canyon, Wupatki National Monument -- negatives and color slides, 1961, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cacti -- negatives and color slides, circa 1960-1970, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Dude Ranches, unknown location: 61 Ranch, Round-Up Ranch, miscellaneous ranches -- negatives, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified aerials and scenics -- negatives, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Native American Event -- color slides (restricted), 1961 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Oversize Arizona, 1939-1950, 1975, 1984; Subseries 3
    This series is described at box level and has no organization. It contains mostly black and white and some color oversize reproductions of images from the second set of series within the collection.
    - Contents include Arivaca, AZ – scenery, Benson, AZ – drive-in movie theater, Elgin, AZ – scenery, Sedona, AZ – Chapel of the Holy Cross and wagon wheel, Willcox, AZ – Three Links Cattle Ranch, 1939-1950, 1975, 1984 (Box 10A)
    - Sells, AZ – Apache Cowboy (Pablo) (restricted), undated (Box 10B)
- United States and Mexico, circa 1936-1960; Series 3
  This series has three sub-series and contains black and white negatives and prints, color slides and postcards from trips to California, Montana and Mexico.
  - United States, circa 1940-1960; Subseries 1
    This series is described at folder level and contains color slides, black and white negatives and prints and postcards from Magee's travels outside of the state of Arizona to McLeod, Montana and popular destinations in California.
    - California: Death Valley -- negatives, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - California: Hearst Castle -- color slides, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - California: Mission San Juan Capistrano, Western Ways -- negatives and color slides, 1962, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - California: Redwood Forest in Yosemite -- color slides, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - California: San Diego Zoo -- negatives, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - California: Palm Springs and Palm Desert Area, Western Ways -- negatives, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Montana: McLeod postcards, Western Ways -- negatives, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Mexico, 1936-1937; Subseries 2
    This series is described at folder level and contains black and white negatives and prints from Gene and Pauline Magee's trip to Mexico in 1936 or 1937.
    - Father Kino's Missions: Caborca, Pitiquito, Tubutama, Atil, Oquitoa, St. Ignacio, Magdalena, Tumacacori, San Xavier, Western Ways -- prints, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Magdalena, St. Ignacio Mission, bell of Atil -- negatives and prints, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Mexico Trip -- negatives, 1936-1937 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Mexico Trip -- negatives and prints, 1936-1937 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Rancho Alamo -- negatives, 1940, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Towns: Guayamos, Playa de Cortes, Pitiquito -- negatives, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Oversize prints from Mexico and California, 1936-1937, 1940; Subseries 3
    This series is described at box level and has no organization.
    - Contains a three-page travel log written by Gene's wife Pauline Magee describing sights and sounds from their trip to Mexico and black and white prints of Mexican city scenes, markets, cathedrals, bull fights, Father Kino's missions, portraits of locals, country scenes, villages and Mesoamerican ruins. The series also includes a few prints from California with images from Death Valley (1940) and one image from Mission San Juan Capistrano, 1936-1937, 1940 (Box 11A)
- Printed Materials, 1952, 1972, 1978, 1996; Series 4
  This series is described at folder level and contains letters to Magee and miscellaneous printed materials such as a West University Neighborhood Association newsletter and an issue of the magazine Creative Ideas in Glass.
  - Letters, 1952, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1972, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)